# CHEN-YI HUANG

Certified Kubernetes Administrator, dedicated software engineer, persistent learner, and enthusiastic open source contributor. Have 6 years experience in Python and 3 years experience in Linux administration. Skilled in automation of system administration, operation, monitoring, and cloud-native solution such as Kubernetes and Containerization. Confident in self-learning and large-scale code tracing. I'm honored to receive the Arctic Code Vault Contributor at GitHub and give short talks about Kubernetes metrics at K8s summit in 2021.

# Skills

Observability Prometheus, Grafana, System & Kubernetes monitoring, Loki, Promtail

VM, Container Kubernetes, Docker, Linux SysAdmin, Nvidia Cloud-Native Technologies, Proxmox

Programming Python, Golang, C, Rust, PromQL

System, Networking Linux SysAdmin, TCP/IP, Wireshark, Chrome DevTools

IaC, CI/CD Ansible, Github Actions, Azure Pipelines

Language Chinese (native), English

# Work Experience

May 2021-Present Senior Engineer, Intelligent Banking Division, E.SUN Bank Taipei, Taiwan

- O Designed & built up a robust monitoring/alerting system that collect 15+ GB metrics per day across 100+ servers.
- O Experienced in Kubernetes administration & cluster and service migration for 8 cluster (60+ nodes) with **95%** & **99%** SLA.
- Adopted automation tool to construct production-grade and GPU-accelerated k8s cluster, and contributed to upstream Kubespray & backported to existing playbook.
- O Developed tools for automating process of daily routine, config management, app deployment, system validation task, which lead to effectively reduce operational costs.
- O Documented thorough k8s installation and operation guide that help pre-trained member deploying a cluster within 1 day.
- O Assisted colleagues in resolving the issue in Ansible, Linux SysAdmin, and Kubernetes.

Oct 2020-Jan 2021 Engineer, Computer Integration Manufacturer, TSMC Hsinchu, Taiwan

- O Developed the web crawler to download hundreds of candidate resumes and general resume parser which achieved up to 95% extracted information accuracy.
- Wrote integration-test under possible scenarios and detailed documents including building procedure and class diagram for senior's project.
- O Pioneer of Robotic Process Automation and efficient i18n support for reporting APP.

# Education

2018–2020 Master of Data Science, Institute of Data Science & Engineering, National Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan

2014–2018 Bachelor of Science, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan, Taiwan

# **Open Source Contributions**

- Found the redundant calculation of derivative of power function in various deep learning frameworks.
  Ø PyTorch, JAX, Autograd
- Support kubeadm v1beta3 patches in both InitConfiguration and JoinConfiguration

@ kubespray

Bug reporting

- @ Python extension for Visual Studio Code
- O Participation of issue discussion.

@ Windows Subsystem for Linux

# Talks & Slides share

Dec 2021 The Journey to the Kubernetes metrics @ Kubernetes Summit 2021

May 2019 Buddy System

# Projects

# May 2022 DCGM exporter extended for aliyun gpushare

- O Support aliyun gpushare-scheduler-extender in Nvidia dcgm-exporter
- O Provide k8s GPU instrumentation, monitoring solution in memory usage (MB) level

# March 2021 Web Assembly rendering in Rust Playground

- O Renderred and displayed Web Assembly from compiled Rust code.
- O Support both Rust Playground (React) and mdBook (native JS) frontend rendering
- O Support various wasm crates including wasm-pack, yew etc.

#### June 2020 Real-time Traffic Anomaly Detector

- Anomaly detection in NCTU administration networks.
- Designed and implemented the data pre-processing pipeline with Apache Kafka, Spark and MongoDB.
- Processed data-stream in real time up to 30 kB/sec and transformed into feature vectors to further predict.

#### Sep 2019 AutoDiff from Scratch

- O Simple neural network library supporting auto-differentiation
- Reported an issue and solved it in various deep-learning libraries during the development.
- O Enabled high-level layer usage and had already tested on real-world dataset.

# Master thesis

Title Solving Traveling Salesman Problem with the Kernel-enabled Attention

Supervisor Shi-Chun Tsai

Description We built on top of the prior state-of-the-art work who borrow the Transformer to solve the TSP. Motivated by the implicit dot product inside the kernel methods, we replace the scaled dot product with kernel in the attention mechanism. In our experiment, we archive shorter tour with a similar approach.

# Certification & Award

- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)
- Arctic Code Vault Contributor @ GitHub